<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fix Navigation</string>
    <string name="ComputerScience">Computer Science</string>
    <string name="brief_history_computer_science">
        Computer science traces its roots back to the early 19th century when Charles Babbage conceptualized the first mechanical computer, and Ada Lovelace wrote the first algorithm intended for machine processing. The field evolved significantly during the 20th century with Alan Turing’s theoretical foundations, the development of the first electronic computers during World War II, and the birth of programming languages like FORTRAN and COBOL. The emergence of personal computers in the 1970s, the internet in the 1990s, and rapid advances in artificial intelligence and software engineering have shaped computer science into a key discipline that drives innovation in nearly every aspect of modern life.\n\n
        Computing jobs are among the highest paid today, and computer science professionals report high job satisfaction. Most computer scientists hold at least a bachelor\'s degree in computer science or a related field.\n\n
        Principal areas of study and careers within computer science include artificial intelligence, computer systems and networks, security, database systems, human-computer interaction, vision and graphics, numerical analysis, programming languages, software engineering, bioinformatics, and theory of computing.\n\n
        Some common job titles for computer scientists include: Computer Programmer, Information Technology Specialist, Data Scientist, Web Optimization Specialist, Database Administrator, Systems Analyst, Web Developer, Quality Assurance Engineer, Business Intelligence Analyst, Systems Engineer, Product Manager, Software Engineer, Hardware Engineer, Front-End Developer, Back-End Developer, Full-Stack Developer, Mobile Developer, Network Administrator, Chief Information Officer, Security Analyst, Video Game Developer, and Health Information Technician.
    </string>

    <string name="what_is_it">Information Technology (IT) is the use of computers, storage, networking devices, and other infrastructure to create, process, store, secure, and exchange electronic data.</string>
    <string name="history_of_it">
        The history of Information Technology (IT) began in the mid-20th century with the invention of the first electronic computers. Early innovations were driven by the need to solve complex mathematical and military problems during World War II, leading to groundbreaking machines like the ENIAC and UNIVAC.\n\n
        In the 1950s and 60s, mainframe computers were introduced, revolutionizing data processing in businesses, government agencies, and large institutions. These powerful machines required specialized environments and were operated by trained personnel, marking the rise of professional IT roles.\n\n
        The invention of the microprocessor in the 1970s sparked a major shift. Personal computers (PCs) like the Apple II and IBM PC brought computing power to homes, schools, and small businesses, making technology more accessible to the general public.\n\n
        In the 1990s, the internet transformed communication and information sharing on a global scale. Email, websites, and online services created new industries, reshaped commerce, and connected people in unprecedented ways.\n\n
        Since the 2000s, IT has rapidly evolved with the explosion of mobile devices, cloud computing, big data analytics, cybersecurity innovations, and artificial intelligence. Technologies like smartphones, social media platforms, and virtual collaboration tools have become integral to daily life and business operations.\n\n
        Today, IT plays a central role in nearly every industry, driving advancements in healthcare, education, finance, entertainment, and beyond. The field continues to innovate with emerging trends such as quantum computing, blockchain technology, and the Internet of Things (IoT), ensuring that IT remains a dynamic and essential force in shaping the future.
    </string>

    <string name="cs_diff_it">The difference between Computer Science and Information Technology </string>
    <string name="cs_vs_it">
        Computer Science (CS) focuses on the theory, design, development, and innovation of software, applications, and computational systems. It involves areas such as algorithms, programming languages, data structures, artificial intelligence, machine learning, robotics, and computational theory. CS professionals often work on creating new technologies, improving computational efficiency, and advancing the capabilities of modern computing.\n\n
        Information Technology (IT), on the other hand, emphasizes the practical application, management, and maintenance of technology within organizations. IT covers system administration, networking, database management, cybersecurity, cloud services, and technical support. IT specialists ensure that computer systems and networks run smoothly, securely, and effectively to meet business needs.\n\n
        In summary, Computer Science is centered around inventing and building new technologies, while Information Technology focuses on applying, implementing, and supporting existing technologies to solve real-world problems and optimize organizational operations.
    </string>

</resources>